(シズネ)みんな… もう少しで
封印は完了する！
Everyone... The seal will
be complete very shortly.
最後まで集中して！
(３人)はい！
Maintain your focus until it's over!
- Right!
(三尾)グォー！
クッ！
フッ！
グオー！
(リー)ん？ あっ あぁ!?
What is that?!
何です!? これは！ あぁ～!!
テンテン！ 後ろにバケモノです！
(テンテン)あっ!?
Tenten! There's a monster behind us!
- Huh?!
(シノ)んっ!?
(テンテン)何これ～！
What is that?!
(ヤマト)カカシ先輩 あれは！
(カカシ)しつこいヤツらだ。
Kakashi Senpai! Is that...?
What a persistent bunch.
It's my turn to pay them back for earlier!
ここは ボクが今までのお返しを！
リー あの粘液じゃ
物理攻撃は きかないわ！
Lee, physical attacks
won't work on that slime.
ああ オレの蟲もな。
Neither will my insects...
(キバ)厄介なヤツらだぜ！
(赤丸)ワン！
Cripes, what a nuisance.
Perhaps it's better to leave them
to the two Jonin...
(サイ)ここは
上忍のお二人に任せたほうが…。
(濡羅吏)フフッ…。
I wonder if this is what you'd call "gross".
(サイ)キモイというのは
こういうのを言うのかな。
(３人)いじめてやる～！
- We'll torment you...!
(キバ)あっ！
ワン！
うわぁ～!!
Huh?!
They sure are...Gross.
…にしても キモイな。
Shattered Promise
(紅蓮)鱗児は どうした!?
What happened to Rinji?!
Rinji became part of
my collection, long ago.
(カブト)ボクのコレクションに
なってもらったよ とっくにね。
(ナルト)なに!?
(カブト)ムダに しつこいヤツだった。
What?!
He was such a nuisance...
Continue...eh?
((鱗児 : 引き続き… か？
オレが 大蛇丸様への連絡役を
やってもいいんですけどね。
I'd be happy to be the one
reporting to Lord Orochimaru...
お前が？
You?
(オレは アンタの草として
ずいぶん働いてきた))
I've done many things
for you as your spy.
大蛇丸様のお世話をするのは
ボク一人で十分だ。
Lord Orochimaru doesn't need
anyone besides me to serve him.
クソッ！ 全部 テメエの
計算どおりってわけか！
Damn it! So it's all going
as you planned...
ああ。 大蛇丸様は
やはり優れたお方だ。
Yes... Lord Orochimaru is
an amazing man.
すべては 大蛇丸様の
予想したとおりに ことが運び➡
Everything has gone as he predicted.
紅蓮と幽鬼丸の心は➡
Guren and Yuukimaru's hearts
have become linked so strongly
互いを帰るべき場所だと
思うほどの信頼で結ばれた。
that they trust each other
to be the place to return to.
そこに２人を繋ぐ
宿命的な関係をぶつければ➡
Now, if this close bond is
shattered by their fatal relations
怒りで幽鬼丸は 爆発的な力を
発揮する… はずだった。
Yuukimaru's anger will
release an explosive force.
That was supposed  to be the case...
しかし 母親を殺したのが
紅蓮だと告げても➡
However, even when he learned that
Guren killed his mother...
幽鬼丸の怒りが
爆発することはなかった。
Yuukimaru's anger did not explode.
なぜだ？
Why...? Why is that?!
なぜだ!?
クククク…。
人間の心とは
なんと不思議なものなんだろうね。
The human heart is
such a strange thing, isn't it?
テメエ！ 許さねえ!!
You...are unforgivable!
幽鬼丸と 紅蓮の気持を
何だと思ってんだ！
What the hell are you doing with
Guren and Yuukimaru's feelings?!
人の気持は
お前らのおもちゃじゃねえ！
You don't play with people's feelings!
フン！
お前らの目的はなんだ？
Just what are you guys aiming to do?!
木ノ葉と 暁だけではない。
It's not only the Hidden Leaf
and the Akatsuki...
各隠れ里はこれから
長く激しくぶつかり合う。
but all the Hidden Villages will soon
engage in long, fierce clashes.
大蛇丸様は その乱世となる未来を
見通しておられる。
Lord Orochimaru has his eyes
on that violent future...
そのための三尾であり
幽鬼丸だったんだ。
That was the reason for
the Three-Tails...for Yuukimaru.
わけわかんねえこと
言いやがって！
That's all gibberish to me.
クックックック！
紅蓮！
Guren!
幽鬼丸と行け！
絶対守ってみせろ！
Go with Yuukimaru!
Show me you can protect him!
(紅蓮)ああ 命に代えてもな！
I will! I'll protect him with my life!
ここは通さねえ
お前は オレがぶっとばす！
I won't let you pass.
I'm gonna kick your butt!
フン。
死魂の術！
Dead Soul Jutsu!
紅蓮。
鱗児。
Guren...
Rinji!
約束だ 絶対にお前を守る。
I promise I'll protect you. I will not fail.
紅蓮さん！
Guren!
晶遁 紅の果実。
Crystal Style: Crimson Fruit!
紅蓮さん！
Guren!
大丈夫 すぐに戻ってくるから。
Don't worry. I'll be right back,
so you wait here.
そこで待ってろ。
えっ。
Huh?!
((待っていなさい))
Wait here.
必ず むかえに来る。
I will come back for you no matter what.
あ…。
行かないで
ボクの帰るところは➡
Don't go! Guren, you're the only one
I have to return to!
紅蓮さんのところしか
ないんだ！
心配するな 私は死なない。
Do not worry. I won't  die.
なに!?
What?!
フフフ ムダなことだ。
It's useless.
そもそも 結晶とは
同一の多面体の物質同士が➡
Crystals are formed when
identical polyhedrons
are aligned in a uniform pattern.
均一に整列したときに
生じるものだ。
結晶化するときに
コウモリが発する超音波で➡
I can stop the crystals from forming
by vibrating the air
with the bats' ultrasonic waves.
空気を振動させれば
それを防ぐことができるのさ。
そう はなから お前の晶遁は
オレの敵ではない。
Yes... Your Crystal Style
was never a threat to me.
(鱗児)ムダと言ったはずだ。
Didn't I tell you it's useless?
死んでも 厄介なヤツ。
You're troublesome
even when you're dead.
フッフッフ…。
紅蓮の次は お前だ 幽鬼丸。
After Guren,
it's you...Yuukimaru.
Huh?!
ゴホッ ゴホッ！
うわ～！
させない！
幽鬼丸は 命に代えても守る！
No you don't!
I will protect Yuukimaru with my life!
紅蓮さん！
Guren!
フッ お前の晶遁は
もう通じない。
Your Crystal Style...
won't work anymore.
死人に何をしても ムダなことだ。
Nothing works against the dead.
これで コウモリは操れないだろ。
Now you can't manipulate
your bats, can you?
ぐ…。
晶遁。
Crystal Style!
なにっ？
What--?!
おとなしく
黄泉の世界に戻るがいいさ。
Return to the underworld quietly!
うわ～っ！
あっ！
紅蓮！
Guren!
ダメだ！
No...!
うっ…。
あっ！
いかないで！
Don't go!
術が破れたか。
The Jutsu is broken!
そんな… ウソだろ？
That...can't be...! You said you'd...
You said you'd protect Yuukimaru...!
ずっと ずっと幽鬼丸を
守るんじゃなかったのかよ！
うっ… うわ～っ！
幽鬼丸！
Yuukimaru!
そろそろ 三尾も疲れてくる頃。
The Three-Tails will be
getting tired soon...
一気に決めるわよ！
Then we'll finish it at once.
なんなの？
What?!
Where is the Three-Tails
finding this kind of strength?
いったい 三尾のどこに
まだこんな力が あるっていうの？
(カツユ)わかりません。 ただ急に
チャクラの量が増えたようです。
I'm not sure, but it seems
his Chakra suddenly increased.
うわ～っ！
あっ あ…。
ヤマト 木遁で牽制しろ！
オレがとどめをさす！
Yamato, use your Wood Style
to restrain it.
I will deliver the finishing blow.
Right.
はい！
Lightning Blade!
雷切！
カカシ先輩。
ああ。
Kakashi Senpai.
Yeah.
封印班を捜索。 救出しろ。
Find the Sealing Team
and rescue them!
(みんな)はい！
- Right!
三尾!!
Three-Tails!
強い絆でつながった
紅蓮を失った今➡
The moment he lost Guren,
with whom he shared a strong bond...
遂に 幽鬼丸は
眠っていた力を発揮した。
the latent power in Yuukimaru
was released.
帰るべき場所を失った悲しみが
これほどに 大きかったとはね。
To think that the sadness of losing
the place he should return to
would be so great...
幽鬼丸 やめろ！
Yuukimaru! Stop...!
うわ～っ！
ダメだ！ 痛っ…。
It's no good!
幽鬼丸 聞こえるか？ 幽鬼丸！
Huh?! Yuukimaru!
Can you hear me, Yuukimaru?!
オレだ！ ナルトだ！
It's me! Naruto!
頼む 気づいてくれ！ 幽鬼丸！
Please notice me!
Yuukimaru!
クッ…！
うおぉ!!
Damn it!
クソッ！ 落ち着け…！
Calm down!
うわっ!!
あっ…！
幽鬼丸…。
Yuukimaru...
(カブト)ハッハッハッハッ！
全部壊してしまえ！
Kill them all! Destroy them!
壊してしまえ！ ハッハッハッハッ…！
フンッ！
クッ… オレが止めるしかねえ。
I'll have to stop it.
多重影分身の術！
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
行くぜ！
うおぉ～!!
Let's do it!
うわ～っ!!
チッ！ 螺旋丸が効かねえ！
Damn it! My Rasengan doesn't work!
And yet, I can't use
the Wind Style: Rasen Shuriken.
けど 風遁螺旋手裏剣は使えねえ。
だったら オレにできんのは…！
But what I can do...
口寄せの術！
Summoning Jutsu!
Bro! That's the Three-Tails, right?
(ガマ竜)うわぁ 兄ちゃん！
あれ三尾だよね!?
(ガマ吉)はぁ やっぱり
めんどくさそうなことに➡
It seems things have
gotten out of hand.
なっとるようじゃのう！
じゃなきゃ お前たち呼んだり
しねえってばよ！
I wouldn't call you guys otherwise.
Gamatatsu, get ready for
the Toad Water Pistol!
ガマ竜！ ガマ鉄砲の準備だ！
Right.
了解！
待て ガマ竜！
Wait, Gamatatsu!
Huh?
ん？
何だよ!? 急いでんだよ！
What is it?! We're in a hurry here!
Think hard. The opponent is
a turtle-like beast that lives in the lake.
よく考えてみろ！ 相手は尾獣。
湖に住む
巨大なカメのバケモノじゃろうが！
風遁で 威力をあげてるとはいえ➡
Even if you increase the power
with the Wind Style,
what will be the effect of using
the Toad Water Pistol,
水遁のガマ鉄砲が どんだけ相手に
効くっちゅうんじゃ!?
which is a Water Style Justu?
To beat a Water Style,
you need the Earth Style.
水遁に勝つには
土遁が必要なんじゃ！
だけど！
グズグズしてるひまはねえんだ！
If we keep stalling,
the terrain around here will change!
オレには風遁しかねえんだから
しかたね…！
I only have the Wind Style
so we have no choice--!
あっ！ 風遁!?
Wind Style?!
((オレってば サスケとの相性
よかったんだな。
So I'm a good match
with Sasuke, huh?
(ヤマト)ああ。
雷に勝てるのは風だけだ！
Yes, only wind can defeat lightning.
いや そっちじゃなくて。
え？
No, that's not what I meant.
火を助けて
さらに大きな力にできるのは➡
I mean only the power of wind
can help fire
by making it
an even larger power.
(風の力だけだってことだ))
火遁だったら？
火遁が どうした!?
Fire Style.
What about the Fire Style?
火遁だったらオレの風で…。
ワシ 使えるぞ！
If we had Fire Style, my wind could...
I can use it.
Huh...?! You can use Fire Style?!
えっ お前 火遁できんのか!?
おお！ できるとも！
Yeah, I can!
Why didn't you say that sooner?!
お前なんで
それ早く言わねえんだよ!!
聞かんかったろうが!!
で 火遁がどうした？
You didn't ask!
And? What about the Fire Style?
ああ！ 火遁なら… あっ！
Oh, Fire Style!
もう なんじゃ？ どうした!?
What is it?
クソッ！ いい考えだと思ったのに！
Damn it! I thought it was
a good idea...
じゃけえ 何がどうした
いいよるんじゃ!?
So just tell me what's going on.
いや… 火を助けて
さらに大きな力にできんのは➡
No... I thought we could
help the "Fire"
and make it stronger with my wind.
オレの風しかねえと
思ったんだけど➡
火は 水に弱いんだったよな…。
But fire is weak against water.
ほうか！ なら 水遁を上回る
さらに強力な炎で➡
I see! If the Water Style is
stronger than the fire,
we'll create an even stronger fire,
which will make the water evaporate.
水を蒸発させりゃええんじゃ！
えっ？
Huh?!
Hey, Gamatatsu!
おい ガマ竜。
何？ 兄ちゃん。
What is it, Bro?
急いで里に帰って ガマの油を
たっぷり飲んで戻ってこい。
Go back to the village and drink
all the Toad oil you can!
ええか？ タイムリミットは １分じゃ。
Okay? You have one minute!
I will summon you back in one minute.
１分 経ったら 呼び戻すけんの。
わかった。
Gotcha!
そうか！ 水の代わりに
油で ガマ鉄砲を発射すりゃ➡
I get it! If you use oil instead of
water to fire the Toad Water Pistol,
一面に油が広がる。
the oil will spread everywhere...
そこに ガマ吉の火遁で
油に火をつける!!
Then you'll set the oil on fire
with your Fire Style.
そうじゃ。 これなら
ガマ鉄砲と同じタイミングで発射できる。
That's right.
We can use the same
練習もいらん。
よっしゃ！ いけるぞ!!
幽鬼丸！
紅蓮… お前が守れなかった約束
必ず オレが守ってやる。
ナルト！ １分 経ったぞ。
おう！
口寄せの術！
間に合ったか？
うん。
なんとかね。
うむ 準備はええぞ ナルト。
ああ！
いいか？ この新コラボ忍術で
アイツの顔を焼く。 弱点は目だ。
よし！ 準備は いいか？
ぶっつけ本番じゃけ
失敗は許されんで！
うん 兄ちゃん。
いくぞ ガマ竜。
オーケー。
コラボ忍法 風遁 ガマ油炎弾！
今だ!!
グオ～ッ!!
フゥ… やった…
やったよ 兄ちゃん！
ああ ようやった。
グオ～ッ…。
ひとまず 終わったみてぇだな。
なら ワシらは帰るけん。
ああ サンキュー。
じゃあね。
幽鬼丸…。
うん？
一緒に… 帰ろう。